<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Siouxland Linux Users Group</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://sluglinux.org/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://sluglinux.org/</id><updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Minutes 2014-12-22</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2014-12-22.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>MrTuttle</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2014-12-22:minutes/2014-12-22.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!---
Summary:
--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://sftommyjacks.com/"&gt;TommyJack's Pub&lt;/a&gt;
214 E. 12th St.
Sioux Falls SD
Date: Monday, December 22, 2014
Time: 6:00 PM to whenever&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drink beer (or whatever you like) and talk about computers.  So easy, even an alcoholic baby could do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are welcome!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try not to spill any beer on your computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven people were in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MrTuttle demonstrated &lt;a href="http://www.blender.org/"&gt;Blender&lt;/a&gt; and how he is using it for planning home improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="slug"></category><category term="meetings"></category><category term="blender"></category></entry><entry><title>Informal Get-Together 2014-12-22</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/news/2014-12-18.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-12-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>MrTuttle</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2014-12-18:news/2014-12-18.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have an informal thing going on Monday, December 22. Come down to TommyJack's, drink, hang out, spend too much money on their awesome jukebox, meet new people (maybe), meet old people (probably), and talk about computers. 
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="slug"></category><category term="meeting"></category></entry><entry><title>Designing with Blender</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/news/2014-05-19.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>MrTuttle</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2014-05-19:news/2014-05-19.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-final.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, some techniques for manipulating the size and location of objects will be demonstrated in the course of building a bookshelf.  It requires no previous knowledge of blender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-factorySettings.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the initial setup, blender is configured just like it would be if had been just installed.  If any settings have been changed, just go to &lt;strong&gt;"file"&amp;gt;"Load Factory Settings"&lt;/strong&gt;.  This will bring blender back from the brink even if the startup file gets overwritten with garbage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for useful keyboard shortcuts to know before beginning, &lt;strong&gt;spacebar&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;control-z&lt;/strong&gt; make life much easier.  If any particular menu item or button can't be found, press the &lt;strong&gt;spacebar&lt;/strong&gt;.  This brings up a context-sensitive search window that will display possible operations.  For example, if "snap cursor to selected" can't be found or the keyboard shortcut can't be remembered, type "cursor" into the search field and it can easily be found it the resulting list.  &lt;strong&gt;Control-z&lt;/strong&gt; is there to undo anything that is done in the course of manipulating the scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-imperial.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do is to change the units blender uses to Imperial since the tutorial uses inches for all the lengths.  Sorry rest-of-the-world.  The properties window is on the lower right hand side of the screen.  It has a number of icons across the top of it. The first one is used to select what kind of window it is.  The other icons are used to select which subset of properties are being displayed, called a context. Click the third icon from the left; it has 3 shapes on it.  This is the scene context.  Down in the units section, change the selection from "None" to "Imperial".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-dimensions.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 3D window, there is a plus sign in the upper right corner. Clicking it will open the properties panel.  Notice the difference between the properties panel, which was just opened, and the properties window, which is where the unit type was selected. Pressing &lt;strong&gt;n&lt;/strong&gt; in the 3D window will also open and close the panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scene should already have a cube in it and it should already be selected.  If it isn't, select it using the right mouse button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-firstPiece.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the properties panel, there is a subset titled "Transform".  The properties at the bottom of the set describe the width, length, and height of the object.  When they are manipulated, they affect the scale of the object to match the dimensions.  Math can be performed within these fields.  Type 4'+(1/8)" into the x dimension.  This becomes 4.01' once enter is pressed.  Change the y dimension to 0.75", and the z dimension to 1".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scroll the mouse wheel or control-middle-mouse-drag to zoom in on the piece.  Middle-mouse-drag will orbit around it.  &lt;strong&gt;Shift-b&lt;/strong&gt; can be used to draw a rectangle around whatever needs to be viewed and the view will zoom in accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default view is in perspective mode, recognized by parallel lines converging in the distance.  Orthographic mode, with parallel lines staying parallel, can be entered through the view menu of the 3D window or by pressing &lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt; on the numpad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note the buttons on the numpad are treated differently than similar buttons elsewhere on the keyboard.  For example, &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; on the numpad will move the view to look at the side of the scene, where &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; at the top of the keyboard will move to the third layer of the scene; the layers being visualized by the 2 5x2 grids at the bottom of the 3D window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-addMenu.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shift-a&lt;/strong&gt; will open the add menu.  Add a new cube to the scene by selecting "mesh"&amp;gt;"cube".  This menu can also be accessed through the menubar at the top of the screen by clicking on "Add".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-viewportShading.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screen is looking a little cluttered with the pieces overlapping one another.  Pressing &lt;strong&gt;z&lt;/strong&gt; will change the viewport shading mode to wireframe.  Pressing it again will change it back to shaded.  This can also be achieved with the viewport shading menu located at the bottom of the 3D window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;strong&gt;tab&lt;/strong&gt; while the new piece is selected to enter edit mode.  Now the mesh of the object can be manipulated.  This mode can also be selected using the menu at the bottom of the 3D window.  &lt;strong&gt;Control-tab&lt;/strong&gt; will bring up the Mesh Select Mode.  Change the mode to "Edge". Select the front top edge of the object.  &lt;strong&gt;Shift-s&lt;/strong&gt; brings up the snap menu.  It is also found at "Mesh"&amp;gt;"Snap".  Select "Cursor to Selected".  Press &lt;strong&gt;tab&lt;/strong&gt; to go back into object mode.  Press &lt;strong&gt;control-alt-shift-c&lt;/strong&gt; to bring up the Set Origin menu.  Select "Origin to Cursor".  This can also be done through "Object"&amp;gt;"Transform"&amp;gt;"Origin to Cursor".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-linedUpPieces.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the first piece and go into edit mode.  Select the top back edge.  Snap the cursor to the selected edge.  &lt;strong&gt;Tab&lt;/strong&gt; back into object mode and select the second piece.  Snap it to the 3D cursor using the snap menu.  Change its dimensions to x= 4', y= 1'-(3/4)", and z= 0.5".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the view needs to be re-centered, select one of the pieces with the right mouse button, then select the other piece with shift-right-mouse-button.  This is how multiple pieces are selected.  Center the view on the selected objects with "View"&amp;gt;"Align View"&amp;gt;"View Selected" or with &lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; on the numpad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the second piece and press &lt;strong&gt;shift-d&lt;/strong&gt; to duplicate it.  This will make a copy of the piece and immediately go into grab mode.  In this mode, the piece will be moved around on a plane perpendicular to the view unless it has been locked to and axis.  Press &lt;strong&gt;z&lt;/strong&gt; to lock the movement to the z axis.  Move it below the other pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Move the origin to the right top edge of the newest piece.  Change it's x dimension to 0.5" and the z dimension to 4'-(0.5)".  Line it up with the bottom right edge of the second piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-pivotPoint.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the first piece and &lt;strong&gt;tab&lt;/strong&gt; into edit mode.  Select the front right edge and snap the cursor to it.  &lt;strong&gt;Tab&lt;/strong&gt; out of edit mode and select the newest piece.  &lt;strong&gt;Tab&lt;/strong&gt; into edit mode, &lt;strong&gt;control-tab&lt;/strong&gt; and select "Face", then select the front face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the settings as they are now, transformation operations are done relative to the center of whatever is selected.  This relative point is called the pivot point.  Press &lt;strong&gt;s&lt;/strong&gt; and move the mouse around a little.  The shape of the face and it's center remain the same but the size changes.  Pressing &lt;strong&gt;x&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;strong&gt;y&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;z&lt;/strong&gt; will limit this transformation to the particular axis.  Pressing &lt;strong&gt;shift-x&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;shift-y&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;shift-z&lt;/strong&gt; will prevent the transformation from happening on that axis.  Right mouse click to cancel the transformation as the settings are not ready to correctly model the piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pivot point needs to be changed to the cursor.  This is done by pressing &lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; on the keyboard or by using the "Pivot Point" menu located next to the "Viewport Shading" menu described earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;strong&gt;s&lt;/strong&gt; and move the mouse around.  Now the way the face is scaled is completely different.  Press &lt;strong&gt;y&lt;/strong&gt; to lock the transformation to the y axis.  As the mouse gets farther from the pivot point, the face moves farther from it as well.  When the mouse gets closer, the face lines up with the pivot point.  Press &lt;strong&gt;0&lt;/strong&gt; then &lt;strong&gt;enter&lt;/strong&gt; and the face will be perfectly lined up with the cursor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-rawBoolean.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem now is the new piece and the first piece are now intersecting one another.  The first piece can be subtracted from the new piece by using a boolean modifier.  In the properties window, click the wrench icon at the top.  This displays the modifier context.  Click the "Add Modifier" button and select boolean.  Under object, select "Cube", which is the name of the first piece created.  Change the operation to "Difference". Finally, click the "Apply" button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-finalBoolean.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check to make sure the operation didn't mangle the piece.  With the newest piece still selected, press &lt;strong&gt;control-i&lt;/strong&gt; to invert the selection.  Pressing &lt;strong&gt;h&lt;/strong&gt; will hide all selected objects.  Now only the newest piece should be visible.  Press &lt;strong&gt;z&lt;/strong&gt; if viewport shading is still set to wireframe.  Make sure the piece doesn't have any weird faces where there shouldn't be.  If there are, some vertices may have to be removed.  &lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt; can be used to remove them.  If a necessary face gets destroyed, it can be recreated by selecting the vertices that made it up, then pressing &lt;strong&gt;f&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the piece looks correct, &lt;strong&gt;tab&lt;/strong&gt; back into object mode.  Everything can be unhidden by pressing &lt;strong&gt;alt-h&lt;/strong&gt;.  Select the front piece and snap the cursor to it.  Select the newest piece and go into edit mode. Pressing &lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt; with something selected with deselect everything. Pressing it again will select everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-mirroredSides.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With everything selected and the pivot point still set to the cursor, duplicate the piece with &lt;strong&gt;shift-d&lt;/strong&gt;, press &lt;strong&gt;s&lt;/strong&gt; to scale it, press &lt;strong&gt;x&lt;/strong&gt; to lock the transformation to the x axis, then type -1, and finally &lt;strong&gt;enter&lt;/strong&gt;. This will make a mirrored copy of whatever is selected, centered where ever the pivot point is located.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-edgesSelected.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the back inner edges of each side piece with shift-right-mouse-click.  Duplicate the edges with &lt;strong&gt;shift-d&lt;/strong&gt;.  Moving the mouse around a little shows the new edges are not connected to the other pieces at all.  Right mouse click to cancel the transformation.  The duplication of the edges still occurred; all that was canceled was the transformation.  With the new edges still selected, press &lt;strong&gt;p&lt;/strong&gt; and select "Selection" to separate them into their own object.  &lt;strong&gt;Tab&lt;/strong&gt; into object mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-backFinished.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Placing the mouse cursor where the new edges where created and right clicking will bounce between selecting the new edges and the sides. Select the new edges and tab into edit mode.  Select everything by pressing &lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt; and create a new face by pressing &lt;strong&gt;f&lt;/strong&gt;.  With the new face selected, press &lt;strong&gt;e&lt;/strong&gt; to begin extruding it.  Extruding is like the previous duplication process but the new face is still connected to the old face.  By doing this, an new cube is being created by hand. Just like the duplication process, right clicking will cancel the transformation of the new face but not the creation of it.  Cancel the translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the properties panel, under the median values, are two buttons: global and local.  These refer to how the median values are interpreted.  The default is local.  If half an inch is subtracted from one of these values while local is selected, that half an inch measurement will be subjected to the scaling of that axis.  If the object is scaled along the y-axis 0.5, the half an inch transformation of the median will have a global effect of only a quarter of an inch.  For this operation to work, global should be selected.  Left click on the y value of the median and subtract 0.5" from the value already there, 11.625"-0.5".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select the inner bottom edge of the back piece and snap the cursor to it.  Make a duplicate of the second piece created, the one that forms the top of the bookshelf.  Snap it to the cursor.  Press &lt;strong&gt;r&lt;/strong&gt; to begin rotating it.  Press &lt;strong&gt;x&lt;/strong&gt; to lock it to the x axis, then type 180, then &lt;strong&gt;enter&lt;/strong&gt; to flip it over.  Change its x dimension to 4'-1" and its y dimension to 1'-0.5".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duplicate this bottom piece a couple times to make the individual shelves.  Using the techniques described, try to make the shelves all evenly spaced apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo" src="http://sluglinux.org/news/Bookshelf-completedBookshelf.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once all the pieces are created and in place, select them all and join them together with control-j.  Place the origin some place useful like the back bottom edge.  This makes it easy to place in a more complex scene like an apartment.  It could even be textured now but that is another tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;shortcuts used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;  spacebar = search function
  ctrl-z = undo
  n = opens the properties panel
  shift-b = zoom boarder
  numpad = manipulates view
  shift-a = add menu
  z = switch between solid and wireframe viewport shading modes
  tab = switch between object and edit mode
  ctrl-tab = mesh select mode
  shift-s = opens the snap menu
  ctrl-alt-shift-c = set origin menu
  .(numpad) = center view on selected
  shift-d = duplicates whatever is selected
  .(keyboard) = moves the pivot point to the 3D cursor
  g = grab
  s = scale
  r = rotate
  x(transformation) = locks transformation to the x axis
  y(transformation) = locks transformation to the y axis
  z(transformation) = locks transformation to the z axis
  ctrl-i = invert selection
  h = hide selection
  x = removes whatever is selected
  f = creates new vertices, edges, and faces
  alt-h = un-hide hidden
  a = select/deselect everything
  p = separate selected vertices, edges, and faces from current object
  f = extrude selected vertices, edges, or faces
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="blender"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2014-03-13</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2014-03-13.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2014-03-13:minutes/2014-03-13.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!---
Summary:
--&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Main Branch, Downtown Sioux Falls Room: Main
Conference Room Date: Thursday, March 13, 2014 Time: 6:00 PM to 9:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plans are nothing; planning is everything. - Dwight D. Eisenhower&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My experience using the animation program, Blender, for CAD - Mr. Tuttle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ownCloud 6 - nickermire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to add items to the agenda!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you secure your Linux system?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virt-Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ZFS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TT-RSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/?mlat=43.54935&amp;amp;mlon&amp;gt;=-96.72901&amp;amp;zoom=1"&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=sioux+falls,+sd+main+library&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ll=43.54805&amp;gt;,-96.729984&amp;amp;spn=0.04025,0.083084&amp;amp;sll=44.2127,-100.247164&amp;amp;sspn=5.094294,10.634766&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;hq=main+library&amp;amp;hnear=Sioux+Falls,+Minnehaha,+South+Dakota&amp;amp;z=1"&gt;Google
maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="owncloud"></category><category term="blender"></category><category term="cad"></category><category term="virtualization"></category><category term="zfs"></category><category term="filesystems"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2014-01-16</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2014-01-16.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2014-01-16:minutes/2014-01-16.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Main Branch&lt;br /&gt;
Room: Main Meeting Room B&lt;br /&gt;
Date: Thursday, January 16, 2014&lt;br /&gt;
Time: 6:00 PM to 8:30 PM  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still moving forward with quarterly meetings.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next meeting will be in January 2014 to avoid holiday plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrating from screen to tmux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;weechat, relays and the weechat android app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wayland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owncloud 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keepass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TT-RSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel free to add items to the agenda!
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/?mlat=43.54935&amp;amp;mlon&amp;gt;=-96.72901&amp;amp;zoom=12
OpenStreetMa"&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=sioux+falls,+sd+main+library&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ll=43.54805&amp;gt;,-96.729984&amp;amp;spn=0.04025,0.083084&amp;amp;sll=44.2127,-100.247164&amp;amp;sspn=5.094294,10.634766&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;hq=main+library&amp;amp;hnear=Sioux+Falls,+Minnehaha,+South+Dakota&amp;amp;z=14
Google map"&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="weechat"></category><category term="irc"></category><category term="screen"></category><category term="tmux"></category><category term="wayland"></category><category term="owncloud"></category><category term="keepass"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2013-09-19</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2013-09-19.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2013-09-19:minutes/2013-09-19.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Main Branch&lt;br /&gt;
Room: Main Meeting Room B&lt;br /&gt;
Date: Thursday, September 19, 2013&lt;br /&gt;
Time: 6:00 PM to 8:30 PM  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next meeting is to be in January instead of December to avoid
    interfering with holiday plans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We spoke a little about different filesystems such as ZFS, ext3,
    ext4, btrfs, ReiserFS and ZFS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pypy.org/"&gt;PyPy&lt;/a&gt; was brought up as a faster implementation
    of the python interpreter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a good time to try &lt;a href="http://www.linuxfromscratch.org/lfs/"&gt;LFS&lt;/a&gt;
    (Linux From Scratch) because recently both it and
    &lt;a href="http://www.linuxfromscratch.org/blfs/"&gt;BLFS&lt;/a&gt; had major releases,
    which doesn't often happen. This is significant because more
    packages will likely be tested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sparkleshare.org/"&gt;SparkleShare&lt;/a&gt; is a privately hostable,
    Dropbox-like system that uses Git as the storage back-end and ssh
    for transport.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://torproject.org/"&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General discussion about &lt;a href="https://www.torproject.org/about/overview.html.en#thesolution"&gt;how Tor
    works&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More specific discussion about &lt;a href="https://www.torproject.org/docs/bridges.html.en"&gt;Tor
    bridges&lt;/a&gt;, and
    why they are useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://crypto.cat/"&gt;Cryptocat&lt;/a&gt; was brought up, but not
    successfully demonstrated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://0bin.net/"&gt;0bin&lt;/a&gt; was brought up in discussion, it is a
    &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pastebin"&gt;pastebin&lt;/a&gt; that encrypts the
    paste using JavaScript and a key passed through the &lt;a href="http://blog.lunatech.com/2009/02/03/what-every-web-developer-must-know-about-url-encoding#GeneralURLsyntax"&gt;fragment
    portion of the
    URL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://joeyh.name/code/etckeeper/"&gt;etckeeper&lt;/a&gt;
    (&lt;a href="https://github.com/joeyh/etckeeper"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;) came up in
    conversation, but wasn't widely used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sabayon.org/"&gt;Sabayon&lt;/a&gt; came up as a distribution easier
    to get started with than &lt;a href="http://www.gentoo.org/"&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We watched a video for &lt;a href="http://elementaryos.org/"&gt;elementary OS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://smartos.org/"&gt;SmartOS&lt;/a&gt; came up, but no one had used it yet.
    &lt;a href="http://openindiana.org/"&gt;OpenIndiana&lt;/a&gt; also came up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimal Linux distributions came up, including
    &lt;a href="http://www.finnix.org/"&gt;Finnix&lt;/a&gt;,
    &lt;a href="http://www.raspbian.org/"&gt;Raspbian&lt;/a&gt;, and
    &lt;a href="http://crunchbang.org/"&gt;CrunchBang&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://nodejs.org/"&gt;node.js&lt;/a&gt; was also a topic of some discussion.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As was some of the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/JavaScript#History"&gt;History of
    JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other programming related discussion included
    &lt;a href="http://clojure.org/"&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; and
    &lt;a href="http://www.clojurescript.net/"&gt;ClojureScript&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was some &lt;a href="http://www.perl.org/"&gt;Perl&lt;/a&gt; discussion, that segued
    into good programming practices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System services and daemons were also discussed, which brought up
    &lt;a href="http://mmonit.com/monit/"&gt;Monit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://mmonit.com/"&gt;M/Monit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="linux from scratch"></category><category term="sparkleshare"></category><category term="distros"></category><category term="monit"></category><category term="perl"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2013-06-20</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2013-06-20.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2013-06-20:minutes/2013-06-20.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Main Branch&lt;br /&gt;
Room: Main Meeting Room B&lt;br /&gt;
Date: Thursday, June 20, 2013&lt;br /&gt;
Time: 6:00 PM to 8:30 PM  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects I have been working on are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xmonad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;synergy 3 computer 4 monitor setup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gitlab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;update from squeeze to wheezy stable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;migrate from apache to nginx&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using rdiff-backup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tmux and screen
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to add items to the agenda!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/?mlat=43.54935&amp;amp;mlon&amp;gt;=-96.72901&amp;amp;zoom=12
OpenStreetMa"&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=sioux+falls,+sd+main+library&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ll=43.54805&amp;gt;,-96.729984&amp;amp;spn=0.04025,0.083084&amp;amp;sll=44.2127,-100.247164&amp;amp;sspn=5.094294,10.634766&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;hq=main+library&amp;amp;hnear=Sioux+Falls,+Minnehaha,+South+Dakota&amp;amp;z=14
Google map"&gt;Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="xmonad"></category><category term="synergy"></category><category term="gitlab"></category><category term="debian"></category><category term="apache"></category><category term="nginx"></category><category term="rdiff-backup"></category><category term="tmux"></category><category term="screen"></category></entry><entry><title>New meeting and new location on June 20th 2013</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/news/2013-05-31.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2013-05-31:news/2013-05-31.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next meeting will be held at a new location, the Siouxland Libraries Main branch downtown Sioux Falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is to have plenty of topics to discuss. If there is interest we can go over these topics in depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the ideas that we have so far are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://xmonad.org/"&gt;xmonad tiling window manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href="http://synergy-foss.org/"&gt;synergy&lt;/a&gt; 3 computer, 4 monitor setup with keybindings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://gitlab.org/"&gt;gitlab&lt;/a&gt; A self hosted "github clone".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;updating from Debian squeeze to &lt;a href="http://www.debian.org/releases/stable/"&gt;wheezy stable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrating from apache to &lt;a href="http://wiki.nginx.org/Main"&gt;nginx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using &lt;a href="http://rdiff-backup.nongnu.org/"&gt;rdiff-backup&lt;/a&gt; for local and remote incremental backups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://tmux.sourceforge.net/"&gt;tmux&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/screen/"&gt;screen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we don't get a chance to cover during this meeting can be pushed to the next meeting. You can submit your ideas to the mailing list by sending an email to sluglinux@googlegroups.com. Please check out the meeting page for more information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;</summary><category term="slug"></category><category term="meetings"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2013-01-17</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2013-01-17.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2013-01-17:minutes/2013-01-17.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch, Room 3 at 6:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel free to add to topics you would like to discuss!
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from the west, take Sixth Street east to
North Bahnson Ave. Turn left at the light, and drive three blocks north
to Third Street. The library is located at the northeast corner of the
intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the east, drive west from Sycamore Avenue on Third Street until you
near North Bahnson (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2012-12-20</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2012-12-20.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2012-12-20:minutes/2012-12-20.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch, Room 3 at 6:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation on NAS by phliver
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to add to the list of topics to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from the west, take Sixth Street east to
North Bahnson Ave. Turn left at the light, and drive three blocks north
to Third Street. The library is located at the northeast corner of the
intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the east, drive west from Sycamore Avenue on Third Street until you
near North Bahnson (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="presentation"></category><category term="nas"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2012-11-15</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2012-11-15.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2012-11-15:minutes/2012-11-15.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch, Room 3 at 6:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steam on linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opello demonstrated his Raspberry Pi
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from the west, take Sixth Street east to
North Bahnson Ave. Turn left at the light, and drive three blocks north
to Third Street. The library is located at the northeast corner of the
intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the east, drive west from Sycamore Avenue on Third Street until you
near North Bahnson (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="steam"></category><category term="raspberry pi"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2012-10-18</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2012-10-18.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2012-10-18:minutes/2012-10-18.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch, Room 3 at 6:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 5 pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A general help session will begin at 5:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MrTuttle spoke about some bad decisions he made in his life that led
    to getting the cops called on him.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration is now open for &lt;a href="http://southdakotacodecamp.net/"&gt;South Dakota Code
    Camp&lt;/a&gt;. Visit the site to register.
    The Event takes place on Nov. 10th from 8:00 am to 5:00 pm. at
    Colorado Technical University. Opello obtained a &lt;a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/"&gt;Raspberry
    Pi&lt;/a&gt; that he will be presenting at the
    South Dakota Code Camp and is looking for ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to add to the list.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="programming"></category><category term="raspberry pi"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2012-07-19</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2012-07-19.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2012-07-19:minutes/2012-07-19.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Notice&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been having a summery cookout instead of a meeting. We should
decide if we want to have something like that again or just a regular
meeting.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now we will plan to just have a meeting, but should certainly
consider the social event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also not sure whether we have the library room reserved for July.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch, Room 3 at 6:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 5 pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A general help session will begin at 5:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's open mic night at the Siouxland Linux User Group!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you've been working on, or what Linux software you can't
live without, or maybe just what's on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to add to the list of topics to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from the west, take Sixth Street east to
North Bahnson Ave. Turn left at the light, and drive three blocks north
to Third Street. The library is located at the northeast corner of the
intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the east, drive west from Sycamore Avenue on Third Street until you
near North Bahnson (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TODO&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="cookout"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2012-06-21</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2012-06-21.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2012-06-21:minutes/2012-06-21.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch, Room 3 at 6:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 5 pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A general help session will begin at 5:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's open mic night at the Siouxland Linux User Group!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you've been working on, or what Linux software you can't
live without, or maybe just what's on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to add to the list of topics to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from the west, take Sixth Street east to
North Bahnson Ave. Turn left at the light, and drive three blocks north
to Third Street. The library is located at the northeast corner of the
intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the east, drive west from Sycamore Avenue on Third Street until you
near North Bahnson (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two new people showed up at 5:30 PM but nobody was there for general
help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At approximately 6:30 PM, Dan and Rob arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fielded general questions about Linux and Open Source. Brief
discussion about &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0308808/"&gt;Revolution OS
(movie)&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan installed Debian into a virtual machine to play with running
mozilla.org FireFox (instead of IceWeasel). We then walked through
setting up mozilla.org FireFox in &lt;code&gt;/opt&lt;/code&gt; on an IBM ThinkPad T-60 running
Debian Squeeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed various desktop environments. Rob and Dan preferred
&lt;a href="http://fluxbox.org/"&gt;Fluxbox&lt;/a&gt; for being minimal. The Debian laptop was
running &lt;a href="http://www.xfce.org/"&gt;Xfce&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob and Dan had a post-meeting discussion about Arduino and Rob's
thermostat control and home automation projects.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="distros"></category><category term="revolution os"></category><category term="fluxbox"></category><category term="debian"></category><category term="firefox"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2012-05-17</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2012-05-17.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2012-05-17:minutes/2012-05-17.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch, Room 3 at 6:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 5 pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A general help session will begin at 5:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's open mic night at the Siouxland Linux User Group!
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you've been working on, or what Linux software you can't
live without, or maybe just what's on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There'll be plenty of time for you to tell us what new stuff you've been
discovering about GNU/Linux and free / open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to add to the list of topics to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from the west, take Sixth Street east to
North Bahnson Ave. Turn left at the light, and drive three blocks north
to Third Street. The library is located at the northeast corner of the
intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the east, drive west from Sycamore Avenue on Third Street until you
near North Bahnson (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>DokotaCon recap</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/news/2012-04-29.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2012-04-29:news/2012-04-29.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you missed the 2012 &lt;a href="http://dakotacon.org/"&gt;DakotaCon&lt;/a&gt; I have put together some links. If you have anything to contribute please leave it in the comments or &lt;a href="mailto:phliver@gmail.com"&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was quite a bit of activity on the &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/dakotacon"&gt;#dakotacon&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few pictures that people published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sdpb.org/newsite/shows.aspx?MediaID=60666&amp;amp;Parmtype=RADIO&amp;amp;ParmAccessLevel=sdpb-all"&gt;Dr. Josh Pauli and DakotaCon presenter, Jared DeMott, discuss DakotaCon&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.sdpb.org/"&gt;South Dakota Public Broadcasting&lt;/a&gt;. Skip to 22:45 for the dakotacon section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marc_Tobias"&gt;Marc Tobias&lt;/a&gt; was there for a little bit to talk about lock security. He gave away some copies of his book &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/search/ref=as_li_qf_sp_sr_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;keywords=0975947923&amp;amp;tag=siolinusegro-20&amp;amp;index=aps&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325"&gt;OPEN IN THIRTY SECONDS: Cracking One of the Most Secure Locks in America&lt;/a&gt; and some CDs. He mentioned that he did a story with &lt;a href="http://www.keloland.com/"&gt;Keloland news&lt;/a&gt; Let me know if you find a link to the video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During Jon Mccoys speech he handed out a few copies of a disc that contained the software he demonstrated and his speeches. They are hosted on his site &lt;a href="http://www.digitalbodyguard.com/"&gt;digitalbodyguard.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keloland ran a &lt;a href="http://www.keloland.com/NewsDetail6162.cfm?Id=130946"&gt;story&lt;/a&gt; about DakotaCon. 
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="dakotacon"></category><category term="security"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2012-04-19</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2012-04-19.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-04-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2012-04-19:minutes/2012-04-19.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch, Room 3 at 6:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 5 pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A general help session will begin at 5:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's open mic night at the Siouxland Linux User Group!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you've been working on, or what Linux software you can't
live without, or maybe just what's on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There'll be plenty of time for you to tell us what new stuff you've been
discovering about GNU/Linux and free / open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to add to the list of topics to discuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from the west, take Sixth Street east to
North Bahnson Ave. Turn left at the light, and drive three blocks north
to Third Street. The library is located at the northeast corner of the
intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the east, drive west from Sycamore Avenue on Third Street until you
near North Bahnson (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vector demonstrated &lt;a href="http://www.endian.com/us/"&gt;endian&lt;/a&gt; for use as a
content filtering solution in a virtual machine.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="endian"></category><category term="virtualization"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2012-03-15</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2012-03-15.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-03-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2012-03-15:minutes/2012-03-15.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch, Room 3 at 6:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 5 pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A general help session will begin at 5:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's open mic night at the Siouxland Linux User Group!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you've been working on, or what Linux software you can't
live without, or maybe just what's on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There'll be plenty of time for you to tell us what new stuff you've been
discovering about GNU/Linux and free / open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/"&gt;raspberry pi&lt;/a&gt; computer was released. I
would like to hear ideas that some of us have for these.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from the west, take Sixth Street east to
North Bahnson Ave. Turn left at the light, and drive three blocks north
to Third Street. The library is located at the northeast corner of the
intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the east, drive west from Sycamore Avenue on Third Street until you
near North Bahnson (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still needs to have hyperlinks added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussed a few different distros such as &lt;a href="http://www.archlinux.org/"&gt;Arch
    linux&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.debian.org/"&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;,
    &lt;a href="http://linuxmint.com/"&gt;Linux mint&lt;/a&gt;. The new &lt;a href="http://crunchbanglinux.org/"&gt;Crunchbang
    statler&lt;/a&gt; was demonstrated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrated a few monitoring programs such as
    &lt;a href="http://htop.sourceforge.net/"&gt;htop&lt;/a&gt; and
    &lt;a href="http://nmon.sourceforge.net/pmwiki.php"&gt;nmon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDDS with linux installed can be moved over from one system to
    another and still boot (for the most part, I have never seen it not
    work).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vector and phliver both have &lt;a href="http://fonality.com/trixbox/"&gt;trixbox&lt;/a&gt;
    which is based on &lt;a href="http://www.centos.org/"&gt;CentOS&lt;/a&gt; running as
    virtual machines in linux. We discussed using spare android phones
    to make a connection to asterisk so they can be used as cordless
    VOIP phones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/"&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; ideas&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://xbmc.org/"&gt;xbmc&lt;/a&gt; frontend - &lt;a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/archives/571"&gt;xbmc running on a Raspberry
    Pi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hooking it up to a cell phone to do a mobile internet radio
    show. (doable with android?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;car computer. (doable with android?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are alternatives to raspberry pi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We discussed the &lt;a href="http://ampache.org/"&gt;ampache&lt;/a&gt; web based music
    front end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="raspberry pi"></category><category term="nmon"></category><category term="android"></category><category term="xbmc"></category><category term="hdds"></category><category term="trixbox"></category><category term="voip"></category><category term="asterisk"></category><category term="ampache"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2012-02-16</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2012-02-16.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-02-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2012-02-16:minutes/2012-02-16.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch, Room 3 at 6:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 5 pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A general help session will begin at 5:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's open mic night at the Siouxland Linux User Group!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you've been working on, or what Linux software you can't
live without, or maybe just what's on your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There'll be plenty of time for you to tell us what new stuff you've been
discovering about GNU/Linux and free / open source software.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from the west, take Sixth Street east to
North Bahnson Ave. Turn left at the light, and drive three blocks north
to Third Street. The library is located at the northeast corner of the
intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the east, drive west from Sycamore Avenue on Third Street until you
near North Bahnson (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be posted.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2011-01-20</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2011-01-20.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-01-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2011-01-20:minutes/2011-01-20.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch, Room 3 at 6:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room opened at 5 pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A general help session began at 5:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Directions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from the west, take Sixth Street east to
North Bahnson Ave. Turn left at the light, and drive three blocks north
to Third Street. The library is located at the northeast corner of the
intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the east, drive west from Sycamore Avenue on Third Street until you
near North Bahnson (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;FreeNAS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glenn spoke about installing and using FreeNAS &lt;a href="http://freenas.org"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;,
a FreeBSD-based network-attached storage distribution. FreeNAS is a
dedicated distro, which means it completely takes over the computer. It
is not a candidate for dual booting.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two basic installation options are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A full platform install. FreeNAS is written to the hard disk; ideal
    for low-memory installs and customization with FreeBSD packages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An embedded install. The FreeNAS image is installed and runs
    entirely in RAM. An embedded install includes an option for USB
    stick installation: only the FreeBSD image is written to the USB
    device; all data is written to other media.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the installation, just before booting into the fresh
install, FreeNAS presents a screenful of device names and settings that
are essential to making the system usable. Make sure to jot down this
information before rebooting, Glenn said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the system is rebooted, the FreeNAS computer console is no longer
needed, as all configuration and services are administered through the
FreeNAS web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few steps to setting up the FreeNAS box before use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the default local IP address (192.168.1.250), if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the default administrative username and password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable https, which is necessary to enable the ssh server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn off Bonjour (zeroconf), if the FreeNAS box is to be exposed to
    the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add and mount disks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add users (and grant access to services).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FreeNAS offers a number of servers, including http, ftp, ssh, rsync,
Samba, NFS, torrents, uPNP, DynamicDNS, and streaming iTunes/DAAP.
Documentation for configuring these services varies from very good to
non-existent, Glenn said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When compared to an off-the-shelf NAS server, such as CoolmaxNAS,
FreeNAS offers more services, although with a bit more setup. If all you
need are Samba, ftp, and maybe bit torrent, the Coolmax device will take
less power, Glenn said. If you need anything more complex, FreeNAS is a
free solution that can be installed on modest hardware, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Prey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve presented a brief demo of Prey, open source software that lets you
track your own laptop or smart phone, in the event of theft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Prey is installed, the user manages it from the Prey website
&lt;a href="http://preyproject.com"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;. The software supports Mac, Windows, and
Linux, as well as Android. The iPhone and iPad versions of Prey are in
the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve showed the web interface and spoke about the limitations of the
free plans, as well as the benefits of paying a \$5 (or higher) monthly
fee for encrypted communication, more frequent reports, and access to
active hardware scans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To take advantage the software, the Prey user needs to enable a guest
account on the device so the thief can connect to the internet, Steve
said. If the phone or laptop is locked down too much, it will prevent
Prey from filing its reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Program Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group kicked around program ideas for 2011:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data recovery / forensics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clonezilla&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Xen for virtual machines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security testing techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jinzora media server demo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone interested in presenting these or giving any other free software
demos should contact Glenn at dakota.son at gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten people attended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--Submitted by Glenn&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="freenas"></category><category term="bsd"></category><category term="prey"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2010-10-21</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2010-10-21.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2010-10-21:minutes/2010-10-21.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch in Sioux Falls, Room 3 at 6:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam will discuss the differences (and similarities) between BSD and
Linux.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still looking for 5- to 10-minute demos for October's meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've tried a new distribution or found an open source program that
makes your computer more useful, show it to the club. A laptop is
available for these demos, so you don't need to bring your own machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To volunteer, contact Glenn (dakota.son at gmail.com).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepared by Glenn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Intro to BSD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month, the club got a glimpse into the world of the BSD (Berkeley
Software Distribution) operating systems, with comparisons between
FreeBSD to Debian Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berkeley_Software_Distribution"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Berkeley_Software_Distribution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam, who has used FreeBSD since 1997, spoke about how the BSD system
includes both a kernel and userland applications, unlike a Linux
distribution, in which the kernel has been developed separate from the
GNU userland applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.freebsd.org/"&gt;http://www.freebsd.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main configuration tool in BSD is the sysinstall application, which
is run on installation, but can be run to reconfigure system settings at
any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In FreeBSD, upgrades are usually a two-step process, in which the kernel
and userland are upgraded first, followed by any third-party
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam also introduced the FreeBSD ports system. In FreeBSD, software can
be installed either via packages, which are pre-compiled binaries, or
via the ports tree, a directory that contains links to the source code
of thousands of software packages and default makefiles for compiling
them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Port management tools, such as portmaster, provide dependency resolution
similar to Debian's apt-get command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://dougbarton.us/portmaster.html"&gt;http://dougbarton.us/portmaster.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The single most important document when learning FreeBSD is the FreeBSD
Handbook , Adam said. The handbook contains information about Unix
basics, as well as clear How-Tos for advanced topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.freebsd.org/doc/handbook/"&gt;http://www.freebsd.org/doc/handbook/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BSDs generally include a Linux compatibility layer, which allows BSD
users to run Linux applications in a chroot environment. Since the
conversion is only in system calls, the Linux applications run at near
native speed, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam also discussed using GEOM to create a mirrored disk RAID with five
commands, and some of the features of ZFS, the self-healing file system
developed by Sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hackerspace&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve, Dusty, Rob, and Dan are planning to create a local hackerspace. A
hackerspace is a physical space that allows people to meet and work on
projects and participate in workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://hackerspaces.org/wiki/"&gt;http://hackerspaces.org/wiki/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They would like your help and your input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next hackerspace meeting will be at 7 pm on Thursday, Nov. 11, at
the Caribou Coffee shop at 1924 S. Minnesota Ave. in Sioux Falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more info, visit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://mooncitylabs.org"&gt;http://mooncitylabs.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Business&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan and Steve have converted the SLUG's website to a new wiki-based
site. Club members are welcome to register and edit pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Dan and Steve for all their hard work!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Help Session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evening began with a new member reporting problems getting Linux
Mint to work with a Kodak ESP 3 printer and a web cam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Members gave their initial advice, and he was given a web page to check.
Discussion will continue on the mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Attendance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all, 13 people attended the meeting, including two new mailing list
members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;November Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SLUG will meet on Thursday, Nov. 18, at the Siouxland Libraries Oak
View Branch in Room 3. The room will open at 5 pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A general help session will begin at 5:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 6:30 pm, Dusty will show us how to improve our use of The Gimp (GNU
Image Manipulation Program).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome anyone willing to do a 5- to 10-minute demonstration for
November's meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've tried a new distribution or found an open source program that
makes your computer more useful, show it to the club. A laptop is
available for these demos, so you don't need to bring your own machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To volunteer, contact Glenn (dakota.son at gmail.com).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;December topic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dinner at Tommy Jack's Pub - details TBA&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bsd"></category><category term="freebsd"></category><category term="wiki"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2010-09-16</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2010-09-16.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2010-09-16:minutes/2010-09-16.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oak View Branch of the Siouxland Libraries in Sioux Falls, Room 3 at
6:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's open mic night at the Siouxland Linux User Group!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell us what you've been working on, or what Linux software you can't
live without, or maybe just what's on your mind.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rob will discuss what steps he is taking to get virtualization
    rolling under Ubuntu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dan may say a few words about ssh tips and tricks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And, if all else fails, Glenn will give a short demo of Peppermint
    Ice Linux, an easy-to-install web-services oriented distribution
    aimed at netbooks and older hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there will be plenty of time for you to tell us what new stuff
you've been discovering about GNU/Linux and free / open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Live CDs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will have free bootable CDs for folks who want to try GNU/Linux
without installing it on their computer. Distributions will include
Linux Mint 9, Ubuntu 10.04, Kubuntu 10.04, and various flavors of
Debian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from Sixth Street, turn north onto North
Bahnson Ave. and drive three blocks to Third Street. The library is
located at the northeast corner of the intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Sycamore Avenue, turn west on Third Street until you near the North
Bahnson intersection (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepared by Glenn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General Help Session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SLUG meeting began at 5:30 p.m. with a general help session. These
sessions are an informal way to get your vexing GNU/Linux questions
aired -- and probably answered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main session started a little late, as the general discussion was
rolling along pretty well at the meeting's start time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glenn gave a quick overview of Peppermint Linux. Two Linux Mint
developers have stripped down Mint to create Peppermint, a lightweight
distribution focused on web services such as Facebook, Twitter, and
Google Apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional desktop applications are available through the software
manager, but are not included in the default installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://peppermintos.com/"&gt;http://peppermintos.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Virtualization on Ubuntu&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob explained the history of virtualization on Ubuntu and how and why it
broke with Ubuntu 10.04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, your best bet for virtualization on Ubuntu is VirtualBox OSE,
but Canonical is developing Qemu for future releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Qemu is properly configured, a virtual machine running on one Qemu
host can be migrated to a second Qemu host with no downtime, Rob said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://wiki.qemu.org/"&gt;http://wiki.qemu.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/VirtualBox"&gt;http://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SSH&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan explained the ssh command syntax and useful options such as port
dynamic port forwarding and compression (when forwarding X sessions or
transferring large files).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He spoke about using the ssh_config man page as a resource for building
a local ssh config file, and gave examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also spoke about denyhosts, a python program that will track failed
ssh authorization attempts and automatically add problem IP addresses to
the list of denied hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://denyhosts.sourceforge.net/"&gt;http://denyhosts.sourceforge.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Attendance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eleven people were present, including one first-time attendee (from the
mailing list) and three visitors from Sioux City.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;October Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SLUG will meet at 6:30pm on Thursday, October 21, at the Siouxland
Libraries Oak View Branch in Room 3. The room will open at 5pm for
setup. A general help session will begin at 5:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam will discuss the differences (and similarities) between BSD and
Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still looking for 5- to 10-minute demos for October's meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you've tried a new distribution or found an open source program that
makes your computer more useful, show it to the club. A laptop is
available for these demos, so you don't need to bring your own machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To volunteer, contact Glenn (dakota.son at gmail.com).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;November topic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the GIMP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;December topic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Party!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="virtualization"></category><category term="ssh"></category><category term="distros"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2010-08-19</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2010-08-19.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-08-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2010-08-19:minutes/2010-08-19.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oak View Branch of the Siouxland Libraries in Sioux Falls, Room 3 at
6:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Secure Network Tunnels: Configuring OpenVPN - 6:30pm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dustin S. will demonstrate the correct way to configure secure network
tunnels using OpenVPN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OpenVPN allows you to build a virtual private network using Windows,
Linux, and Mac platforms. OpenVPN is a feature-rich, flexible system for
anyone who needs to provide secure network traffic via the internet.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Installation Basics -- New User session at 5:30pm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the regular meeting, Glenn will talk about "Installation Basics,"
reviewing some of the basic steps to install a Linux distribution.
Anyone is welcome to jump in to share advice and experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New User session is also a time for new users to seek help for any
problems they may be having with the Linux learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux experts and novices are encouraged to attend this early session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 5 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Live CDs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will have free bootable CDs for folks who want to try GNU/Linux
without installing it on their computer. Distributions will include
Linux Mint 9, Ubuntu 10.04, Kubuntu 10.04, and various flavors of
Debian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from Sixth Street, turn north onto North
Bahnson Ave. and drive three blocks to Third Street. The library is
located at the northeast corner of the intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Sycamore Avenue, turn west on Third Street until you near the North
Bahnson intersection (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Dustin S. for his presentation on OpenVPN configuration at
last night's SLUG meeting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a bit of discussion about bridged vs. routed VPN configuration,
which hopefully helped some of the folks struggling to make their VPN
installations work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again, Dustin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--Glenn&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="openvpn"></category><category term="install"></category><category term="distros"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2010-06-17</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2010-06-17.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-06-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2010-06-17:minutes/2010-06-17.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oak View Branch of the Siouxland Libraries in Sioux Falls, Room 3 at
6:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Remote Control: Secure Access in GNU/Linux&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dustin and Rob will demonstrate some secure remote access utilities for
controlling Linux, Mac, and Windows boxes over the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a demo night, so once Dustin and Rob are done, anyone can take
the floor and show off some cool and useful software.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Asking the Right Questions -- New User session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the regular meeting, Glenn will present "Asking the Right
Questions," which will give questions that new users should ask before
diving into a Linux distribution. Anyone is welcome to jump in to share
advice and experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New User session is also a time for new users to seek help for any
problems they may be having with the Linux learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux experts and novices are encouraged to attend this early session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 5pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Live CDs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will have free bootable CDs for folks who want to try GNU/Linux
without installing it on their computer. Distributions will include
Linux Mint 9, Ubuntu 10.04, Kubuntu 10.04, Xubuntu 10.04, and various
flavors of Debian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from Sixth Street, turn north onto North
Bahnson Ave. and drive three blocks to Third Street. The library is
located at the northeast corner of the intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Sycamore Avenue, turn west on Third Street until you near the North
Bahnson intersection (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On behalf of the SLUG, I would like to extend a big thank you to Dustin
an Rob for their presentations on Thursday night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both bravely ventured into unknown territory -- using remote control
software over the library's wireless connection -- and both succeeded!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good job, guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;--Glenn&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="demo"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="presentation"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2010-05-20</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2010-05-20.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-05-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2010-05-20:minutes/2010-05-20.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oak View Branch of the Siouxland Libraries in Sioux Falls, Room 3 at
6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Speak Freely: Open Source Voice over IP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steve and Rob will recount their adventures in open source VoIP
applications during May's Siouxland Linux Users Group meeting. They
learned some important lessons about hardware that works (and doesn't
work) and software configuration for VoIP.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meet Linux Mint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New User session at 5:30 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the regular meeting, Glenn will present a brief introduction to
Linux Mint, a more polished version of Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Meet Linux Mint" will kick off the SLUG's New User session, a time for
new users to seek help for any problems they may be having with the
Linux learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux experts and novices are encouraged to attend this early session.
The room will open at 5pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Live CDs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will have free bootable CDs for folks who want to try GNU/Linux
without installing it on their computer. Distributions will include
Linux Mint 8 (and rc 9), Ubuntu 10.04, Kubuntu 10.04, and various
flavors of Debian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Location Directions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to the Oak View branch from the west, take Sixth Street east to
North Bahnson Ave. Turn left at the light, and drive three blocks north
to Third Street. The library is located at the northeast corner of the
intersection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the east, drive west from Sycamore Avenue on Third Street until you
near North Bahnson (about six blocks). The library will be on your
right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join. New members are
welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepared by Glenn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Speak Freely: Open Source Voice over IP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve and Rob gave an overview of voice over IP services currently
available, including the open source
&lt;a href="http://www.asterisk.org/"&gt;Asterisk&lt;/a&gt; server and
&lt;a href="http://www.freepbx.org/"&gt;FreePBX&lt;/a&gt; configuration manager. They also
explained a number of possible configurations of Asterisk for home and
business use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hardware requirements for Asterisk and FreePBX are minimal: Rob uses
an Athlon 64 single core processor and rarely sees a processor load.
Using several codecs (required if you use a mix of phone brands) could
cause the processor load to climb, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specialized modules are available to connect the Asterisk server to
other voice services, such as &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/voice"&gt;Google
Voice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve and Rob also talked about how their Asterisk servers connect to
the telephone system through services like
&lt;a href="http://vitelity.com/"&gt;vitelity.com&lt;/a&gt;, which allow VoIP users to choose
an area code from a list of available numbers. Callers from that area
dial a local number and so do not pay long-distance charges, regardless
of where the VoIP server is located.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also covered the different types of VoIP hardware available, and
issues with 911 calling, which can be addressed by services offered by
VoIP companies like &lt;a href="http://vitelity.com/"&gt;vitelity.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An informal Q-and-A session followed the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New User Session&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SLUG's first New User session kicked off with Glenn giving an
overview of Linux Mint 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux Mint 9, released May 18, is a distribution based on Ubuntu's 10.04
LTS version "Lucid Lynx." Security updates will be available to 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glenn highlighted some of the differences between Mint and other
distributions: the ease of installing and removing software (open or
proprietary), the use of the search function within the Mint Menu, and
the ratings given to system updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants received Linux Mint 9 live CDs to try on their machines at
home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Topic Suggestions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group discussed topics for future meetings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtualization in Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pfsense and m0n0wall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synergy and XDMCP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Attendance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourteen people attended the May meeting.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="voip"></category><category term="distros"></category><category term="mint"></category><category term="synergy"></category><category term="pfsense"></category><category term="m0n0wall"></category><category term="virtualization"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2010-04-15</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2010-04-15.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-04-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2010-04-15:minutes/2010-04-15.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oak View Branch of the Siouxland Libraries in Sioux Falls, Room 3 at
6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High Availability Tools: Keep on Servin'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Dean will cover High Availability tools for Linux at the April
Siouxland Linux Users Group meeting. These tools are critical to the
delivery of enterprise-level services.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 6pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An informal question-and-answer session will follow the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will have free bootable CDs for folks who want to try GNU/Linux
without installing it on their computer. Distributions include Ubuntu,
Kubuntu, Xubuntu, Fedora with Gnome, Fedora with KDE, and various
flavors of Debian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no cost to attend the meeting or to join.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepared by Glenn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Dean gave an overview of &lt;a href="http://www.drbd.org/"&gt;DRBD&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href="http://linux-ha.org/wiki/Heartbeat"&gt;Heartbeat&lt;/a&gt;, two high availability
tools for Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DRBD is used to manage a single data set mirrored on two computers, one
computer acting as the primary server, and the other as secondary. The
computers can be in separate server farms, if desired. Heartbeat works
with DRBD to switch the secondary server to primary quickly and
automatically, if the primary server should fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex went through the configuration files for both programs, and
outlined situations in which both servers may be running, but they each
think the other host has disappeared from the network. This situation
usually occurs more frequently than the loss of a server, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Q-and-A session that followed his talk, he outlined a number of
ways that DRBD and Heartbeat could be used with MySQL database servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His recommended resource for DRBD is &lt;a href="http://www.drbd.org/users-guide"&gt;http://www.drbd.org/users-guide&lt;/a&gt;.
The recommendations for heartbeat are
&lt;a href="http://www.linux-ha.org/HeartbeatTutorials"&gt;http://www.linux-ha.org/HeartbeatTutorials&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://people.linbit.com/~florian/heartbeat-users-guide/"&gt;http://people.linbit.com/~florian/heartbeat-users-guide/&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href="http://www.clusterlabs.org"&gt;http://www.clusterlabs.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex works for IPS MeteoStar in Denver, CO, a company that provides high
availability solutions for weather data worldwide to government and
industry. See &lt;a href="http://weather.meteostar.com/"&gt;http://weather.meteostar.com/&lt;/a&gt; or
www.meteostar.com/company/news.html for more information about IPS
MeteoStar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Topic Suggestions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We gleaned a few more meeting topics from the group:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Little Utilities for non-geeks;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geotagging your digital photographs; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular (monthly) install-fest / help sessions for new Linux users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Attendance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twelve people attended the April meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;May Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve and Rob will present May's topic on VoIP - using the internet for
making phone calls. They have been tweaking their Asterisk servers for a
few months, and should be ready to go at 6:30pm on &lt;a href="Meetings:2010-05-20" title="wikilink"&gt;Thursday, May
20&lt;/a&gt;, at the Oak View Branch meeting room
3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free Linux live CDs will be available for folks who want to try Linux
for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;June Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Topic TBA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;July Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No formal meeting: Barbecue or Pizza Party&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Future topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General help, video streaming, FreeNAS, Utilities for Non-geeks&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ha"></category><category term="kde"></category><category term="distros"></category><category term="heartbeat"></category><category term="drbd"></category><category term="install fest"></category><category term="geotagging"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2010-03-18</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2010-03-18.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-03-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2010-03-18:minutes/2010-03-18.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Oak View Branch near Third St. and North Bahnson,
Room 3 at 6:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 6pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few business items:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plans for upcoming meetings.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High-availability server tools - tentative April topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VoIP - standby April or May topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other business items the group wants to discuss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentations on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux From Scratch - the why and the how&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hulu on Linux demo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live CD demo (if there's time/interest)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclude with an open discussion period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The library closes at 9pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepared by Glenn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Oak View Library gave the group a last-minute room upgrade, which
may have confused members looking for the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Room 3 is empty on meeting night, members should look for a Tux
poster or the current SLUG program poster to find the correct room. The
poster will be displayed at the meeting room door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all else fails, ask a friendly Oak View librarian for directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meeting Plans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group plans to have a picnic or pizza party sometime this summer.
This meeting will be a social event, with no formal presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was some interest in &lt;a href="http://freenas.org/"&gt;FreeNAS&lt;/a&gt;, a
FreeBSD-based distribution for network attached storage. The topic has
been added to the program list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SLUG is still looking for someone with experience in local network
media servers who is willing to give a 30- to 45-minute talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Install Fest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The group discussed organizing an install fest, when and where to hold
one, and how much publicity would be needed. There was general agreement
to include BSD in the offered distributions if someone with BSD
experience can be found.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Linux from Scratch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles explained the process of getting a Linux from Scratch (LFS)
system running. LFS is the distribution he uses for his everyday
computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reasons for running LFS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control - less bloat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security - no need to wait for a maintainer to apply patches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education/Accomplishment - the user will learn about Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation on the LFS website is good, and new users should pay
attention to the manual's clear warnings and alerts, he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles has written shell scripts for the LFS build process to ensure
that the correct commands are executed each time. Charles urged new
users to make a backup image of the LFS partition after Chapter 5 in the
LFS manual, just in case they make a mistake in building the system in
Chapter 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said that his first LFS build took about 60 hours, not including
compile times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once users have a working LFS system, they can either use it as a
command line environment, or they can look at Beyond Linux From Scratch
(BLFS) or one of the other LFS-related projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.linuxfromscratch.org/"&gt;http://www.linuxfromscratch.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hulu Desktop on Linux&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob demonstrated the Hulu Desktop, which is available for Fedora and
Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it uses the Adobe Flash web browser extension, Rob likes the
Hulu Desktop because it does not become bloated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application allows the user to stop playback in the middle of shows.
The next time Hulu Desktop is run, it plays one commercial and then
resumes playback from the stopping point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user can subscribe to shows, and Hulu Desktop will add new episodes
to the user's queue as they become available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hulu.com/labs/hulu-desktop-linux"&gt;http://www.hulu.com/labs/hulu-desktop-linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Live CD Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glenn showed how to access a computer's BIOS and change the drive boot
order, if the machine won't automatically boot from a live CD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Attendance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven people attended the main meeting, including one new member who has
joined the mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;April Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SLUG will meet at 6:30pm on &lt;a href="Meetings:2010-04-15" title="wikilink"&gt;Thursday, April
15&lt;/a&gt;, at the Siouxland Libraries Oak View
Branch in Room 3. The room will open at 6pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Dean will present April's topic: High Availability tools for Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SLUG is still looking for a 5- to 10-minute demonstration for
April's meeting. To volunteer, contact Glenn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free Linux live CDs will be available for folks who want to try Linux
for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;May topic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VoIP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Future topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Video streaming, general help session, FreeNAS, picnic or pizza party.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="linux from scratch"></category><category term="distros"></category><category term="ha"></category><category term="voip"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2010-02-18</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2010-02-18.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-02-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2010-02-18:minutes/2010-02-18.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Siouxland Libraries Ronning Branch near 49th and Southeastern at 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room will open at 6pm for setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few business items:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Program ideas for upcoming meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scouting a permanent meeting location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Places that may be willing to display meeting posters?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other business items the group wants to discuss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presentations on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security testing / Firewall testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hulu on Linux Demo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclude with an open discussion period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The library closes at 9pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepared by Glenn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meeting started with advice to a Microsoft Windows user who was
attending after her machine had been infected by a Windows virus for the
second time.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was encouraged to try a Linux live CD on her machine, as a way of
trying Linux without committing to an installation. The group was
enthusiastic about Linux, but advised her that it may not be a solution
for her if she is interested in running proprietary-only software, such
as iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Program Topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group expressed interest in Alex's offer to present a program on
high-availability tools and/or network monitoring tools. Glenn will
contact Alex about the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group also showed an interest in VoIP on Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Meeting Places&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glenn reported that the Ronning Branch meeting room may not be an ideal
place for the SLUG to meet regularly: The library reserves the right to
preempt the SLUG meetings if the space is needed for a library-sponsored
event or group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SLUG discussed other meeting venues, including restaurants with
meeting rooms and a private conference room. Jerry and Glenn will
explore these options and report at the March meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Publicity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group offered a list of places where meeting posters and SLUG
brochures could be placed. Glenn will incorporate at least some of the
locations in future publicity efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Security Testing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jerry gave an extensive tour of the Linux-based &lt;a href="http://www.untangle.com/"&gt;Untangle
Firewall&lt;/a&gt;, and led discussion about firewalls
and security settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group had a sometimes-spirited discussion about &lt;a href="https://www.grc.com/x/ne.dll?bh0bkyd2"&gt;GRC's
ShieldsUP&lt;/a&gt; website and the
significance of its pass/fail ratings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting time ran out before Rob could give his Hulu on Linux demo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eleven people attended the meeting. One mailing list member stopped in
before the meeting, but had to leave due to a scheduling conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;March Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SLUG will meet again at 6:30pm on &lt;a href="Meetings:2010-03-18" title="wikilink"&gt;Thursday, Mar.
18&lt;/a&gt;, at the Siouxland Libraries - Oak
View Branch in northeast Sioux Falls. The meeting room will open at 6pm
The Oak View Branch is located at 3700 E. Third St., near the
intersection of Third Street and North Bahnson Avenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March's topic -- Linux From Scratch demonstration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone interested in presenting a short (5- to 10-minute) talk and
demonstration in March should contact Glenn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We plan to have free Linux live CDs for anyone interested in trying a
new distribution or in trying Linux for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Future topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VoIP, high-availability tools, video streaming, vendor presentations,
general help session.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="security"></category><category term="firewall"></category><category term="advocacy"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2010-01-21</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2010-01-21.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-01-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2010-01-21:minutes/2010-01-21.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pizza Ranch on 41st St. at 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepared by Glenn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten people gathered for an informal meeting to determine the current
level of interest in open source software and the Siouxland Linux Users
Group.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees shared information about the Linux distributions they run and
discussed troubles compiling Linux from Scratch version 6.5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Favorite web browsers, file system troubles, favorite meta search sites,
search techniques, and Richard Stallman were also topics of a
wide-ranging conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group discussed future meeting times and locations, and the
importance of being consistent, once a schedule and workable location
have been established.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SLUG will meet again at &lt;a href="Meetings:2010-02-18" title="wikilink"&gt;6:30 p.m. on Thursday, Feb.
18&lt;/a&gt;, at the Siouxland Libraries Ronning
Branch in southeast Sioux Falls. The meeting room will open at 6 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;February's topic -- Security Testing / Firewall Testing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a short Hulu on Linux demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group will also have free live CDs available for anyone interested
in trying a new distribution or in trying Linux for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March's topic -- Linux from Scratch demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Future topics -- Video streaming, vendor presentations, general help
session, newbie night.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="linux from scratch"></category><category term="distros"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2009-02-26</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2009-02-26.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2009-02-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2009-02-26:minutes/2009-02-26.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Globe University at 6:30pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers: Steve
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussed the future of SLUG at Globe University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make Fliers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a map and directions page for the website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve demonstrated installing &lt;a href="http://www.pfsense.org/"&gt;pfSense&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussed its relationship with &lt;a href="http://m0n0.ch/wall/"&gt;m0n0wall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits of its package management system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power of BSDs packet filtering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussed how we can help GNU/Linux newcomers and future meeting
    ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing computer programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bringing new people to the meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Possibly working with a rights group at Augie for a presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussed improvements to the website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making changes to reflect current meeting information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="advocacy"></category><category term="bsd"></category><category term="packet filtering"></category><category term="package management"></category><category term="programming"></category><category term="website"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2008-11-26</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2008-11-26.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2008-11-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2008-11-26:minutes/2008-11-26.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pizza Ranch on 41st at 7:00pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Informal meeting
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The usual crowd showed up. Another very informal meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve handed out some comic books that were sent to us by Jeremiah
    Gray. They were GNU/Linux and Ubuntu related and geared towards
    teaching new people about GNU/Linux and Ubuntu. These are new and
    Jeremiah wanted us to give him feedback.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.hackettandbankwell.com/"&gt;Hackett and Bankwell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We talked a little bit about the mailing list going down and our
    move to the google groups list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussed the direction we wanted to go in the future. Such as what
    do we want to accomplish with SLUG. What presentations we should do
    and where we should do them. How to get the word out and other
    potential meeting locations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And of course various chit chat about VPNs, Asterisk, WiFi, and
    other fun things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="mailing list"></category><category term="vpn"></category><category term="asterisk"></category><category term="wifi"></category><category term="comics"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2007-10-18</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2007-10-18.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-10-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2007-10-18:minutes/2007-10-18.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorado Technical University, room 172 at 5:30pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, you're the goto exerpt. Thanks for hanging out here.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2007-09-20</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2007-09-20.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2007-09-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2007-09-20:minutes/2007-09-20.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep thinking - adds a new diemnison to it all.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note taker: phliver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;opello's soekris router&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CF card for data storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated via web interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runs m0n0wall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soekris hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MythTV&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more zap2it labs, moving to Schedules Direct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schedules Direct used to cost \$15 for 90 days, now \$15 for 6
   months. More price drops planned in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schedules Direct is a non profit created by the community. Makes
   it a little easier to justify paying for the service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flash player built in to the MythTV web interface can be found
   in subversion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next version, Gutsy Gibbon (7.10) Blueprints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Release date planned for the 18th of October, 2007&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After Gutsy Gibbon will be the Hardy Herring LTS release (8.04)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phliver will order CDs through ShipIt when Gutsy Gibbon becomes
   available. This way we will get stickers too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discussed BulletProof-X (screenshots).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SLUG&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advertise with the SLUG flyer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talked about printing a few copies of Full Circle Magazine to
   pass around at future meetings. We will start posting new
   releases on our website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We would like to buy some of these Ubuntu logo decals to pass
   out/sell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few of us are going to look into pricing for other Ubuntu/SLUG
   related stickers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misc.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Briefly discussed Buffalo routers and Wireless Distribution
   System, Which is supported by dd-wrt and the like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;O'Reilly books for doing reviews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future presentation ideas. We will videotape these for the
   website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeff showed off his "Linux stamp" prototype (&lt;a href="http://opencircuits.com/Linuxstamp"&gt;project
   page&lt;/a&gt;), and showed videos of
   the process (posted soon).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dusty peeled the windows sticker off of his notebook :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="storage"></category><category term="m0n0wall"></category><category term="mythtv"></category><category term="soekris"></category><category term="ubuntu"></category><category term="distros"></category><category term="advocacy"></category><category term="wifi"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2006-01-19</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2006-01-19.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2006-01-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2006-01-19:minutes/2006-01-19.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This meeting was at the Main Branch of the Siouxland Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday's meeting was good. Brandon Morris performed a presentation on
OpenWRT. Some of the things covered and demonstrated were:
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NVRam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ipkg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bridging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have made the &lt;a href="Media:Meetings-2006-01-19-Openwrt.odp" title="wikilink"&gt;openwrt presentation
file&lt;/a&gt; available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I highly recommend you &lt;a href="http://downloads.openwrt.org/whiterussian/"&gt;download your latest firmware from
openwrt.org&lt;/a&gt;. We used
&lt;a href="Media:Meetings-2006-01-19-openwrt-wrt54g-squashfs.bin" title="wikilink"&gt;openwrt-wrt54g-squashfs.bin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ipkg"></category><category term="networking"></category><category term="openwrt"></category><category term="wifi"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2004-11-19</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2004-11-19.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2004-11-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2004-11-19:minutes/2004-11-19.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Location&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorado Technical University&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Agenda&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brandon (solarce) presented Firefox and Firefox extensions
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Minutes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firefox 1.0 Released November 8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.extensionsmirror.nl/"&gt;http://www.extensionsmirror.nl/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;comprehensive list of Firefox extensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AdBlock&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brandon demonstrates using wildcards to filter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download tweak&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;del.icio.us&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;del.icio.us extension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;del.icio.us/tag/lug&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foxylicious (import del.icio.us bookmarks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting things done with Flashblock&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Puts a play button in place of flash content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyconfig&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remap keybindings for Firefox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Session Saver&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restores your session on crash/shutdown. Configurable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saves default sessions. Morning routine etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conflicts with tabbrowser extensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Single Window&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Force links to open in a new tab or single window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launchy&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helps find helper applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Developer&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of web development tools in a new bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;about:config&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More config options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worried about giving away your email address to register?
    Mailinator.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dan (opello) X.org composites&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shows off fading windows and true transparency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;X.org compositing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Command to turn everything on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;xcompmgr -cCfF -r7 -o.65 -l-10 -t-8 -D7&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xorg.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Section "Extentions"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Option "Composite" "Enable"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Option "RENDER" "Enable"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;EndSection&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For NVIDIA cards, add this option in your "Device Section":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Section "Device"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;Option "RenderAccel" "true"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;code&gt;EndSection&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="firefox"></category><category term="extentions"></category><category term="xorg"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2004-06-18</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2004-06-18.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2004-06-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2004-06-18:minutes/2004-06-18.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorado Technical University, room 139(?) at 5:30pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers: None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some People Attended&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robby was not here to give his presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve, Ben, and I hauled in some computers...&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We couldn't get BSD/Mosix working in time, but hope to for next month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Insert Name] brought in a box of old Intersil WaveLan White and
    Bronze cards, which most attendees grabbed (and some were donated to
    CTU students).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="presentation"></category><category term="wifi"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2004-05-21</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2004-05-21.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2004-05-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2004-05-21:minutes/2004-05-21.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Location: Colorado Technical University, room 139(?) at 5:30pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speakers: None&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11 People Attended&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robby was not here to give his presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smalltalk ensues...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SLUG Recommends: BTTV chipsets for TV Tuner Cards, and MythTV for recording and managing shows.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="presentation"></category><category term="mythtv"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2004-03-19</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2004-03-19.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2004-03-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2004-03-19:minutes/2004-03-19.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorado Technical University, room 135 at 5:30pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: C.J. Steele
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security Beyond the Firewall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service Limiting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://bastille-linux.sourceforge.net/"&gt;Bastille Linux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://grsecurity.net/"&gt;grsecurity&lt;/a&gt; /
    &lt;a href="http://pax.grsecurity.net/docs/"&gt;PaX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IDS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ee.lbl.gov/"&gt;arpwatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.logwatch.org/"&gt;logwatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.snort.org/"&gt;snort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;process monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://mmonit.com/monit/"&gt;monit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://netsaint.sourceforge.net/"&gt;netsaint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;integrity checking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/tripwire/"&gt;tripwire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;layer 7 packet filtering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple firewall script overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also for individual machines, not just a dedicated firewall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;port knocking [&lt;a href="http://www.zeroflux.org/projects/knock"&gt;knockd&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="security"></category><category term="firewall"></category><category term="backups"></category><category term="distros"></category><category term="logwatch"></category><category term="snort"></category><category term="monit"></category><category term="netsaint"></category><category term="tripwire"></category><category term="packet filtering"></category><category term="port knocking"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2004-02-27</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2004-02-27.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2004-02-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2004-02-27:minutes/2004-02-27.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorado Technical University, room 134 at 5:30pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Robby, Packet Shaping
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25 people attended, many were on their first visit to SLUG!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 Minutes of Anticipation ...&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's your linux experience? ranged from total neophyte to 10 years of experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentation: Packet Shaping &lt;a href="http://lartc.org/lartc.html"&gt;http://lartc.org/lartc.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basic filtering can also be done with
        &lt;a href="http://www.netfilter.org/projects/iptables/index.html"&gt;IPTables&lt;/a&gt;
        and marking packets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://leaf.sourceforge.net/"&gt;leaf&lt;/a&gt;,
        &lt;a href="http://m0n0.ch/wall/"&gt;m0n0wall&lt;/a&gt;, and
        &lt;a href="http://www.smoothwall.org/"&gt;smoothwall&lt;/a&gt; are firewall
        distributions
        *   leaf and m0n0wall have traffic shaping capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We had time left over and Dan
    &lt;a href="http://www.gentoo.org/doc/en/handbook/handbook-x86.xml?part=2&amp;amp;chap=1"&gt;emerged&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href="http://www.gnucash.org/"&gt;GNUCash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="packet shaping"></category><category term="presentation"></category><category term="m0n0wall"></category><category term="gentoo"></category><category term="distros"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2004-01-30</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2004-01-30.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2004-01-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2004-01-30:minutes/2004-01-30.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date: January 30, 2004 at 5:30pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizational Meeting
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note taker: opello&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and time of the meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday seems to work out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mailing list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going to a discussions + announcements mailing list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tips and tricks section archived from discussion mailing list showing 'our best tricks'&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meeting room&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are shooting for a public place, and at little or no cost.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be coordinated over the mailing list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install Fest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An install fest might be a good idea.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We decided we should pick a specific distro and stick to it to create less confusion.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick a date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a place with enough room&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;next month - vector doing ip / firewall / tunnels / security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book Reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce and view a sample of the book reviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deciding whether to do a library type concept and check out books, or have drawings for them. looks like we are leaning towards a library idea?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let us know if your willing to do a book review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shirts, Hoodies, Stickers, Case badges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking around for prices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nixon, resident graphics guy, playing around with logos and layouts.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;slogan contest / submit ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SLUG Officers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need slightly more formal system of governing SLUG&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Executive committee to deal with things and be responsible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treasurer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chairperson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various topics of discussion include:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;embedded Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plausible denyability encryption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;various bouts of awkward silence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;voluntary dues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="Install fest"></category><category term="encryption"></category><category term="organizational"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2003-10-24</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2003-10-24.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2003-10-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2003-10-24:minutes/2003-10-24.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Horizons at 5:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Agenda&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topic: Mandrake 9.2 demonstration Speakers: pez4brian
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion: Started on the last install step of Mandrake 9.2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advantages Graphical install&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto Detection and Expert Mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control Center&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard Drake to show hardware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Samba and Apache Config tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boot graphics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;splash screen with progress bar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you get rid of? Was the major question&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install of programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;dependency checking for RPM installs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disadvantages Mandrake specific RPM package naming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this makes it difficult to use third party RPM to satisfy dependencies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions: How to get rid of splash screen?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linux Server Hacks book was raffled&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;LAN Party&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started at 6:30 pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quake III&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="networking"></category><category term="samba"></category><category term="graphics"></category><category term="package management"></category><category term="lan party"></category><category term="mandrake"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2003-09-26</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2003-09-26.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2003-09-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2003-09-26:minutes/2003-09-26.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was our first SLUG/ LAN meeting and was a learning experience. We
had a new show, however with confusion and time I was unable to get any
information about him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tried to work with an &lt;a href="http://www.ipcop.org/"&gt;IPCOP&lt;/a&gt; box and did not get
too far with that as the person who knew what was going on with it was
unable to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest outcome of this meeting was learning that we need more of an
agenda and structure to run the meetings and get the most information in
the least time. This is all getting worked on to make improvements on
the meetings.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next meeting will hopefully have a presentation of some sort
followed by a LAN party. As trying to do both did not work out as we
wanted. So gear up and suggest some ideas for a presentation for the
next meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note the next meeting will be held on Fri October
24th 2003 due to the last Friday being Halloween!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="lan party"></category><category term="ipcop"></category><category term="distros"></category><category term="organizational"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2003-07-05</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2003-07-05.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2003-07-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2003-07-05:minutes/2003-07-05.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Minutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So due to lack of time sorry it took so long---&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;phliver&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;opello&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mikey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pez4brian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cassie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But3rfly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian brought in his linux box with mandrake on it. However, did not get
much discussion on it. Please message me with the specs so we can go
over it an the next meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install of 2.6 Kernel on But3rfly's machine to see if it would fix the
sound issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some talk about dependency hell... a vote for possible new meeting
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least! Phliver bring da switch next time!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="distros"></category><category term="audio"></category></entry><entry><title>Minutes 2003-06-30</title><link href="http://sluglinux.org/minutes/2003-06-30.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2003-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>stevenix</name></author><id>tag:sluglinux.org,2003-06-30:minutes/2003-06-30.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;!-- PELICAN_BEGIN_SUMMARY --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a good meeting! Monday may be a possibility for future meetings
as it seems to work out for most of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set up &lt;a href="http://synergy2.sourceforge.net/"&gt;synergy&lt;/a&gt; on two linux
machines and found that it was WAY too easy, it didn't take long at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussed the current status of the website and the sluglinux.org
domain. Talked about a few distros, gentoo and mandrake in particular.
&lt;!-- PELICAN_END_SUMMARY --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="synergy"></category><category term="website"></category><category term="distros"></category></entry></feed>